<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News Archives - Watch Ndcs Undp</title>
	<atom:link href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/category/news/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 04:51:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Coach of Zambia Women&#8217;s World Cup team accused of sexual misconduct, report claims</title>
		<link>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/coach-of-zambia-womens-world-cup-team-accused-of-sexual-misconduct-report-claims/</link>
					<comments>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/coach-of-zambia-womens-world-cup-team-accused-of-sexual-misconduct-report-claims/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 04:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/?p=137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coach of Zambia Women&#8217;s World Cup team accused of sexual misconduct, report claims The coach of the Zambia team preparing to make its debut at the Women’s World Cup has been accused of sexual misconduct and the case was referred to world body FIFA last year for investigation, according to a report in The Guardian newspaper. ... <a title="Coach of Zambia Women&#8217;s World Cup team accused of sexual misconduct, report claims" class="read-more" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/coach-of-zambia-womens-world-cup-team-accused-of-sexual-misconduct-report-claims/" aria-label="More on Coach of Zambia Women&#8217;s World Cup team accused of sexual misconduct, report claims">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/coach-of-zambia-womens-world-cup-team-accused-of-sexual-misconduct-report-claims/">Coach of Zambia Women&#8217;s World Cup team accused of sexual misconduct, report claims</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org">Watch Ndcs Undp</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Coach of Zambia Women&#8217;s World Cup team accused of sexual misconduct, report claims</p>



<p>The coach of the Zambia team preparing to make its debut at the Women’s World Cup has been accused of sexual misconduct and the case was referred to world body FIFA last year for investigation, according to a report in The Guardian newspaper.</p>



<p>Bruce Mwape was accused of coercing players into having sex with him if they wanted to keep their place on the team, according to the report published by the British newspaper on Saturday.</p>



<p>Other Zambian coaches and officials were also accused of sexual misconduct and investigated, including the Under-17 girls’ team coach, according to the paper.<a href="https://apnews.com/article/womens-world-cup-sinclair-schmidt-sheridan-a7014cb2dfb70de4a4f9e58a5093c7e6"></a></p>



<p>Christine Sinclair will lead the Canadian women’s national team at the upcoming Women’s World Cup. Sinclair, international soccer’s all-time leading scorer among men and women, is playing in her sixth World Cup.<a href="https://apnews.com/article/rodman-us-wales-world-cup-sendoff-cc7a49af53ff54962155e0c0b5d663d1"></a></p>



<p>Rising star Trinity Rodman scored for U.S. in the 76th minute and again in the 88th, and the Americans finally capitalized on their many offensive chances to beat Wales 2-0 in a final tuneup for the Women’s World Cup.<a href="https://apnews.com/article/liv-golf-cam-smith-reed-dustin-johnson-3060273ac1b8d387d1e89e5fcf228242"></a></p>



<p>Cameron Smith has his first victory of the year. The Australian shot a 68 on Sunday to win LIV Golf-London by one stroke over Patrick Reed and Marc Leishman<a href="https://apnews.com/article/mirra-andreeva-16-teen-wimbledon-e82b4d27aa9f54d892c401e119723ac0"></a></p>



<p>Mirra Andreeva didn’t go far when she needed some advice after losing in the third round at her first major tennis tournament.</p>



<p>Zambia soccer association president Andrew Kamanga confirmed in a message to The Associated Press on Sunday that allegations of sexual misconduct were referred to FIFA and Zambian police last year and said it was “an old story.” Kamanga didn’t name any of the people facing allegations of wrongdoing.</p>



<p>In line with protocol, FIFA said its independent ethics committee would not comment on whether or not there was an investigation underway.</p>



<p>Zambia’s soccer association launched its own investigation last year but also didn’t name any officials, coaches or players involved at the time. The Zambian association said when it made the announcement in September that it was taking the allegations seriously.</p>



<p>But The Guardian quoted an anonymous source as saying that the Zambian association was “turning a blind eye” to the allegations because of the recent success of its women’s team under Mwape.</p>



<p>Zambia qualified for the Tokyo Olympics in 2021 and the World Cup in Australia and New Zealand, which starts this month. The men’s team has never made it to the World Cup.</p>



<p>Zambia on Friday had a surprising 3-2 win over two-time World Cup winner Germany in a warmup game for this year’s tournament. Zambia captain and star striker Barbra Banda scored twice, including the winning goal in the 12th minute of added time.</p>



<p>Banda has been at the center of another controversy for the Zambian soccer association after she was withdrawn from last year’s Women’s African Cup of Nations because of a bungled sex eligibility case.</p>



<p>Zambia’s football association removed Banda from its squad for the tournament over sex eligibility rules despite Banda being cleared to play at the Olympics and at the World Cup. The association and the African soccer confederation blamed each other for mishandling Banda’s case.</p>



<p>Zambia is in Group C at the World Cup with Spain, Costa Rica and Japan and plays its first game against the Japanese on July 22.</p>



<p>Mwape was featured in an interview on the FIFA website in May, when he spoke about taking Zambia to the World Cup for the first time.</p>



<p>In the interview, he said that the team’s achievement had “changed football in Zambia” by inspiring many girls to start playing.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/coach-of-zambia-womens-world-cup-team-accused-of-sexual-misconduct-report-claims/">Coach of Zambia Women&#8217;s World Cup team accused of sexual misconduct, report claims</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org">Watch Ndcs Undp</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/coach-of-zambia-womens-world-cup-team-accused-of-sexual-misconduct-report-claims/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US soccer media reflects on Megan Rapinoe&#8217;s retirement</title>
		<link>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/us-soccer-media-reflects-on-megan-rapinoes-retirement/</link>
					<comments>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/us-soccer-media-reflects-on-megan-rapinoes-retirement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 04:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/?p=134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>US soccer media reflects on Megan Rapinoe&#8217;s retirement After the 2023 National Women’s Soccer League season and the 2023 FIFA Women’s World Cup, Megan Rapinoe plans to retire from professional soccer. The news was announced during a press conference on Saturday by the two-time World Cup winner. The US Womens National Team (USWNT) has described Rapinoe as a ... <a title="US soccer media reflects on Megan Rapinoe&#8217;s retirement" class="read-more" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/us-soccer-media-reflects-on-megan-rapinoes-retirement/" aria-label="More on US soccer media reflects on Megan Rapinoe&#8217;s retirement">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/us-soccer-media-reflects-on-megan-rapinoes-retirement/">US soccer media reflects on Megan Rapinoe&#8217;s retirement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org">Watch Ndcs Undp</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>US soccer media reflects on Megan Rapinoe&#8217;s retirement</p>



<p>After the 2023 National Women’s Soccer League season and the 2023 FIFA Women’s World Cup, Megan Rapinoe plans to retire from professional soccer.</p>



<p>The news was announced during a press conference on Saturday by the two-time World Cup winner.</p>



<p>The US Womens National Team (USWNT) has described Rapinoe as a player renowned for her exceptional skills in the game, her inventive goal-scoring abilities, her critical contributions in high-stakes games, and her profound commitment to a range of societal issues such as LGBTQ+ rights, racial disparity, voting rights, and gender and wage equality.</p>



<p>Thus, she exits the sport as one of the most influential personalities in U.S. soccer history and within the worldwide women’s soccer community.</p>



<p>After finishing the 2023 NWSL season with her long-time team OL Reign, she will retire from professional soccer after participating in her last World Cup this summer in Australia and New Zealand.</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Megan Rapinoe opens up on retirement plans</h5>



<p>“I’ve been able to have such an incredible career, and this game has brought me all over the world and allowed me to meet so many amazing people.</p>



<p>I feel incredibly grateful to have played as long as I have, to be as successful as we’ve been, and to have been a part of a generation of players who undoubtedly left the game better than they found it. To be able to play one last World Cup and one last NWSL season and go out on my own terms is incredibly special.</p>



<p>“I want to thank my family for being by my side all these years. Thanks to all my teammates and coaches all the way back to my first days in Redding, on to college at the University of Portland and of course thanks to U.S. Soccer, the Seattle Reign and especially Sue, for everything.</p>



<p>I will forever cherish the friendships and support over the years in this game, and I am beyond excited for one last ride with the National Team and the Reign”, she said at the press conference.</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">What US soccer media thinks about Rapinoe’s retirement</h5>



<p>“It’s what she has done off the field that will define her legacy and be remembered as her biggest victories.” —&nbsp;Kevin Baxter, LA Times</p>



<p>“More and more players support causes these days but Rapinoe was in many ways a pioneer of that. 199 games for her country (and counting) but for much of the world she is more famous for her political activism than her skills on the field. That is unique.” —&nbsp;Simon Evans, Reuters</p>



<p>“Her role has changed, undoubtedly, but there’s never been any doubt about what Rapinoe has brought to this team as a leader, a locker room presence, a fighter, sometimes even a bit of a trickster god on the field, doing things simply out of joy or curiosity or sheer humor.” — Meg Linehan, The Athletic</p>



<p>“It has always been the moments and the creativity of her offense, not the volume of goals or assists, that truly set Rapinoe apart.” — Claire Fahy, New York Times</p>



<p>“Audacious. Progressive. Entertaining. Thoughtful. Choosing even a few superlatives to describe the incredible soccer career of Megan Rapinoe is a difficult task. She is a legend among legends, even in a United States women’s national team program replete with all-time greats.” — Jeff Kassouf, Equalizer Soccer</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/us-soccer-media-reflects-on-megan-rapinoes-retirement/">US soccer media reflects on Megan Rapinoe&#8217;s retirement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org">Watch Ndcs Undp</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/us-soccer-media-reflects-on-megan-rapinoes-retirement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Potential for Danish soccer rebellion may put FIFA to test</title>
		<link>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/potential-for-danish-soccer-rebellion-may-put-fifa-to-test/</link>
					<comments>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/potential-for-danish-soccer-rebellion-may-put-fifa-to-test/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 04:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/?p=131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Potential for Danish soccer rebellion may put FIFA to test Whether you call it soccer, football, or something else entirely, it’s undeniable that it’s the most popular sport on the globe. Soccer has an unprecedented degree of relevance and impact, with an estimated 4 billion supporters worldwide. The significance of FIFA to the soccer community ... <a title="Potential for Danish soccer rebellion may put FIFA to test" class="read-more" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/potential-for-danish-soccer-rebellion-may-put-fifa-to-test/" aria-label="More on Potential for Danish soccer rebellion may put FIFA to test">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/potential-for-danish-soccer-rebellion-may-put-fifa-to-test/">Potential for Danish soccer rebellion may put FIFA to test</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org">Watch Ndcs Undp</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Potential for Danish soccer rebellion may put FIFA to test</p>



<p>Whether you call it soccer, football, or something else entirely, it’s undeniable that it’s the most popular sport on the globe.</p>



<p>Soccer has an unprecedented degree of relevance and impact, with an estimated 4 billion supporters worldwide.</p>



<p>The significance of FIFA to the soccer community is immense. Since its inception in 1904, the international governing body has been instrumental in developing soccer into a worldwide phenomenon.</p>



<p>The international events it organizes draw huge crowds and serve as a unifying force for countries worldwide because of the organization’s role as the sport’s regulatory body.</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Denmark plotting breaking away from FIFA</h5>



<p>But is FIFA essential to the game of soccer?</p>



<p>In contrast, the Danish football association hinted at an unexpected radicalism last November, when the rainbow armband scandal was at its height ahead of the 2022 World Cup in Qatar.</p>



<p>When asked whether Denmark would contemplate withdrawing from FIFA, the DBU president Jesper Moller said: “It is not a decision that has been made now … We have been discussing it in the Nordic region since August … I have to think about the question of how to restore confidence in FIFA. We must evaluate what has happened, and then we must create a strategy – also with our Nordic colleagues.”</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">What it would mean for other big nations</h5>



<p>The Guardian columnist Jonathan Wilson criticizes FIFA president Gianni Infantino for caring only about money and maintaining his own power. No one was asked for input before unveiling the enlarged World Cup and Club World Cup. The columnist also fights that Infantino relies heavily on Gulf money in his quest for control of Uefa. In order to host the World Cup in Qatar, FIFA had to make some disgraceful concessions, such as ignoring Article 4 of its own statutes, which forbids discrimination based on ethnicity, gender, religion, or sexual orientation.</p>



<p>The major European countries may rise up against Infantino’s rule if they became tired of the expansion of tournaments or, implausibly, for ethical reasons. Fifa would have a serious issue on its hands if the World Cup were played without Argentina, Brazil, France, Germany, Spain, or England.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/potential-for-danish-soccer-rebellion-may-put-fifa-to-test/">Potential for Danish soccer rebellion may put FIFA to test</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://watch.ndcs.undp.org">Watch Ndcs Undp</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://watch.ndcs.undp.org/potential-for-danish-soccer-rebellion-may-put-fifa-to-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
